Shujaullah Ahsan

87 Skyline drive apt# 2, Braintree, 02184 | 857-266-1803 | ahsanshuaj1127@gmail.com

OBJECTIVES

Software Engineer with thorough hands-on experience in web development, latest technologies. Project Manager, strong decision-maker, enthusiastic and dedicated team player with the aim to serve the industry with the best of my skills. Currently learning and working on UMASS Boston CS-Portal using Django.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Javascript, Python, R, SQL PLUS, Racket.

Others: HTML, CSS, Git, Linux, Django.

Tools: VS Code, Github, Visual Studio, Atom, Intelli j, eclipse, android-studio, PyCharm,

EXPERIENCE

01/2020 - present

UMB Unix Lab Operator

Tutor of CS and IT students.

Maintain a log of all computers in the domain

- Maintain Unix accounts for CS and IT students.
- Manage a directory of CS students
- Currently working on the CS department projects to manage their database by using Django.

12/27/2019- Present

The concierge at Constellation wharf

Charles Town, Ma

Boston, Ma

- Complete exchanges and returns in a timely and professional manner.
- Help with the organization of on-site events including business fairs, and corporate meetings.
- Process important queries and manage customer expectations in a polite and friendly manner.

PROJECTS:

Personal Portfolio

- Personal Portfolio that demonstrates CS projects, skills, and work experience.
- Used HTML, CSS, and is to build that application.

Bookstore Project

- The program displays the books and sorts books according to book ids.
- The program allows users to buy or rent the book and put them in the queue.
- The program used all of the data structure algorithms like searching, sorting, link list, dynamic arrays, etc

Weather App

- Built an android app that displays the weather of the current city. Users could also search for other cities
- The app also feathers hourly and daily weather for the current city.

Compiler

- Built a compiler based on java's compiler
- It scans for recognized tokens, parses the tokens to create a parse tree and checks for syntax errors, and analyzes the parse tree to check for type errors.
- Used java bytecode instructions to generate code

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts, Boston

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Dean's List

September 2019 – Present

Quincy College

• Associate of Science, summa cum laude, Computer Science

September 2017 – May 2019

Related Courses

 Advanced Java, Advanced C++, Unix with Linux, Data Structures with Java, Advanced Theory of Computation, Computer Architecture, Higher-level languages, Operating systems, Database management, Web development, and robotics, C Programming., Compilers, android development.

AWARDS

2020 UMASS Boston Computer Science Scholarship.

 Selected into 2020 Paul English scholarship. The scholarship is awarded only to people with having a high GPA in the computer science department.

2018 Quincy College Codeathon Winner

• Team member of the project which is a Voice app designed on a Rasberry Pi to provide info to students inquiring about courses. Use regular expressions to parse the data from the Google Assistant API.